The American speech music. All cultures gesture, and recently a developmental
physiologist at University of Wisconsin, Dr. Ali Bali, put forth that gestures
accompany speech because our mouths and hands are closely linked in the brain. You
may have noticed babies saying ga ga ga and moving their hands to the beat. It's
not necessary for you to gesticulate wildly, but it is important to integrate
the rhythm of your speech music with physical gestures. To this end, you'll be
tapping the table, snapping your fingers, and maybe even stretching a rubber band.
my language? A Pakistani database analyst said, I didn't think about my own language
in this way before. There is intonation when we speak, but not as much as in
American English. Now that I've analyzed it, I found my language to be rhythmic
too. In many places, we do the same up and down intonation. I must not have realized
it because I speak without thinking about the language itself. It's really
interesting to compare both language styles and then to extract certain
resemblances from them. I never thought of it in that way.